

Marco Maida Computer scientist



13 August 1994



github.com/marcomaida



00marcomaida00@gmail.com

About me ———

I am a computer scientist currently pursuing a PhD at Max Planck Institute for Software Systems.

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers since I have memory. In 2013, I started working professionally as a programmer. After three years, I decided to start a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer. Once I graduated, I moved to Kaiserslautern, Germany, and started a Master+PhD program.

I completed all my master courses, and recently published my first work.

Languages ———

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am very fluent in English,

und ich spreche auch etwas **Deutsch**.

Extras —

I like doing new and many things, especially if they involve science, nature, music, sport, food or traveling • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • Probably sometimes I talk too much • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have nine years of professional experience in writing code. I am fluent in writing **Python**, **C#**, **C++**, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. During my seven years in the **industry**, I learn to work on big code bases in large and small teams.

Having spent two years in **research**, I can study complicated problems and then design, implement, evaluate, document and finally present my solutions.

I am very **outgoing** and, in my experience, I do well in teams. Being a relevant part of my career in game development, I am used to collaborate with different professional figures and over time I developed a good sense of **aesthetics**.

Education

| since 2019 | Ph.D. student Real-time Systems group | Max Planck Institute for Software Systems |
|------------|--|---|
| since 2019 | Master in Computer Science | Technische Universität Kaiserslautern |
| 2016-2019 | Bachelor in Computer Science (110/100 cum laude) | Università degli studi di Torino |
| 2015-2016 | Game dev: Software Development (30/30) | t Event Horizon School |
| 2008-2013 | Diploma in Computer Science (98/100) | ITIS A. Avogadro |

Experience

since 2019 **Computer Science Researcher.**

Max Planck Institute

I am currently working on Real-time Systems. My work is focused on timeliness certifications in safety-critical systems using formal verification (Coq) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux.

2016-2019 Game developer.

34BigThings

I worked with Unity3D and Unreal Engine on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Nintendo Switch and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, tools and UIs.

2016 Freelance Unity3D developer.

Teoresi, Choralia, Maserati

I worked as a freelance developer, building interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D (C#) and shipping on

mobile devices and browsers.

2013-2016 Software engineer.

R.O. sr

I worked as a software developer using C++, C/CLI, C# and SQL building software solutions for glass processing factories. In this company I covered many roles, including traveling to customers to sell, install and teach our softwares.

Other Projects

2018 Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit.

I developed an open-source Unity3D framework to quickly develop production-ready mobile games. The framework restricts the game type to infinite-runners, but imposes no restriction on the actual gameplay, and automatically handles data persistence, ads, analytics, and a leveling system. Complementary to this, I developed a Python toolkit to automate the creation and updating of the FMC games. With a small team composed of me, an artist, and a designer, we developed ten production-ready games within a month. (www.github.com/340penThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4.

I developed a framework that connects gameplay with Razer's Chroma devices, used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)